Richard Chinonso Udeji

Email: nonsorichard7@gmail.com

GitHub: https://github.com/nonsorichard7

OBJECTIVE

A well determined physics graduate with a keen interest in web technology, who loves exploring the web in general. I am very much interested in the entry level position and I believe I am a great fit for the job. Reasons being that I possess excellent, on the job skills needed for the said work as I am already well grounded in web development and programming, teamwork, and a superb work experience in a prestigious company similar to what I believe is expected at your company.

I am excited to work with Bincom and I can not wait to contribute to its digital management.

EDUCATION

2016 - 2020

Veritas University, Bwari, Abuja.

BSc Physics with Electronics.

Some Relevant courses offered:

- Numerical methods and analysis, java, c++, python, computational physics, quantum mechanics, computer debugging, computer algorithms.
- Graduated with a second-class upper division and a 4.6 gpa in my final year.
- Used Python to perform complex data manipulation, and conduct data visualization and analysis.
- Contributed in the making and maintenance of the university's school website using software developer tools and languages like html, css and Javascript.
- My university project on "the Yukawa Potential and Ground State Energy" was the first of its kind and the only publication by the school from the department.

EXPERIENCE

MAY 2022 - DECEMBER 2023

Pure Web Technologies, Abuja, Nigeria - Software Engineer Intern.

 Worked with Client partners and internal teams to design and develop APIs services, build performant front-end applications using the latest tools and techniques

- Built internal tooling with the team of engineers
- Tools & Technologies: JavaScript React, Redux, REST, MongoDB // Webpack, CI/CD.

OCTOBER 2022 - DECEMBER 2022

Zuri Internship Training - Front End Developer Intern

- Worked with slack, an online platform that helps connect people together to work as teammates to improve work performance.
- Hands-on experience with over 20 frontend development projects to help improve programming skills.
- Worked with several programming languages like html css JavaScript, react, nodejs, express, mongodb for both frontend and back end development.

SKILLS

Core: HTML5, CSS3 (TailwindCSS, Bootstrap, CSS-in-JS, SCSS), TypeScript, JavaScript (*React, NextJS, Styled components, Redux, Node*), *SWR, AWS (Amplify, S3)*, CI/CD with GitLab, Jest, MongoDB, APIs.

Want to learn: Go, Cloud infrastructure.

Soft Skills: Presentation and Public Speaking, Teamwork, Problem Solving, Verbal and Oral Communication.